Guide to the Greenwich House Photographs Collection PHOTOS.066
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Greenwich House Photographs
1902-1991
1902-1969
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Greenwich House (New York, N.Y.)
Gulkin, Anita Kurman
PHOTOS.066
12 Linear Feet (19 boxes)
In 1902, Mary Kingsbury Simkhovitch and others founded Greenwich House, a social settlement house in the Greenwich Village section of New York City. It was incorporated that year as the Cooperative Social Settlement Society of the City of New York. Greenwich House established social service and cultural programs for the largely immigrant population of Greenwich Village. The Greenwich House Photographs Collection contains a unique group of images pertaining to social welfare and the settlement movement over a period of more than seventy years. The images are strongest in documenting the programs of Greenwich House (particularly those involving children and fine and applied arts instruction, such as its Pottery School and Music School, and its nursery school and kindergarten programs, and summer camps), as well as its administrative and institutional activities. The Collection also documents many aspects of the lives of immigrants and working people in New York City: Greenwich House social events, for example, detail the complex interactions between different ethnic groups, as well as the dress and demeanor of working-class children in New York City. In addition, street vistas document the architectural history of New York City and offer information on community life in Greenwich Village.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Greenwich House donated a collection of their photographs to Tamiment Library in 1986. The accession number associated with this gift is 1986.002. The University Archives transferred photographs of Greenwich House to Tamiment in 1996, the accession number associated with this gift is NPA.1996.011. Additional photographs were donated to Tamiment after the initial accession, the accession numbers associated with these gifts are NPA.2000.284, NPA.2001.004, and NPA.2004.073.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged first by format (e.g., photographic prints, negatives, etc.); within format they are stored in individual folders that are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Folder titles include subjects, events, and names of persons and organizations; they also indicate the total number of images and dates of material contained within a folder. Where dates of images have definitely been identified, they are rendered on folders as individual years and/or as year or decade ranges, while images for which dates are completely unknown are designated as "undated." Where an image or images cannot be definitely dated, but enough information is available to make an educated guess, this is indicated on the folder and on the finding aid container list by enclosing the guessed date or dates within square brackets (e.g., [1910s-1950s] or [1954, 1960s]). Definitely dated materials are followed by guessed dates or the undated designation (e.g., 1964, [1940s-1970s] or 1928-1952, undated) on all folders. Within folders, images are physically arranged in date order, with undated material (including guessed dates) following dated material. Negatives that have matching prints are cross-referenced.
Organized into 4 series:
Missing Title
I: Photographic Prints, 8 x 10" and smaller, 1902-1991.
II: Slides, 1978, undated.
III: Negatives, undated.
IV: Oversized and Mounted Photographic Prints, circa 1890s-1960, undated.
Historical/Biographical Note
Greenwich House was incorporated in 1902 as the Cooperative Social Settlement Society of the City of New York by Mary Kingsbury Simkhovitch with Felix Adler, R. Fulton Cutting, Eugene A. Philbin, Henry C. Potter, Jacob Riis, and Carl Schurz. Working out of a renovated tenement house at 26 Jones Street, Greenwich House's first challenges were to work to reduce the debilitating infant mortality rate in Greenwich Village, then the highest in New York City, and to ameliorate the oppressive social conditions that attended the neighborhood's population congestion. Its first director, Mary Simkhovitch, agitated for better living conditions, playgrounds, child labor laws, and sanitary measures, and implemented the Settlement's programmatic scheme to address the pressing needs of the community. Two classic studies published in the pre?World War I years, Mary Ovington's Half a Man and Louise Boland More's Wage Earner's Budget: A Study of Standards and Costs of Living in New York City, were products of Greenwich House's Social Investigation Committee. The Tenant's Manual, published in 1903, was the first of its kind to document tenement laws and tenants' rights.
Beyond its pioneering work in housing reform, Greenwich House set programmatic innovations in other areas. The Nursery School, founded in 1921, was the first and prototypical program of its kind in New York City. Simkhovitch, an ardent advocate of cultural programs, believed the arts to be essential human services. By l917, when Greenwich House relocated to 27 Barrow Street, it offered music, theatre and fine arts programs onsite and also established art classes in many local public schools. The Greenwich House Arts Committee was initiated with the support of Mrs. Payne Whitney, who later founded the Whitney Museum.
By the end of the First World War, Greenwich House had clearly expanded its role beyond that of a small social service dispensary. Integral to its growth and success were its residents, the young social workers and middle-class reformers who lived in the settlement house and who frequently worked with promising leaders developed from the client population. In addition to its cultural agenda and housing reform activities, it provided vital institutional support for government programs, a function that further solidified in the l930's when many programs of the Works Projects Administration were housed at the Settlement.
Settlement houses, and their leaders, were also key advocates for reform. Mary Simkhovitch was no exception, her efforts were central to the passage of the U.S. Housing Act of 1937, which provided for federal aid to build low-income housing. Greenwich House has been a Village fixture for more than one-hundred years. Among its many thousand anonymous beneficiaries are a number of now familiar people including actors Kirk Douglas and Rip Torn, both of whom performed on the Greenwich House stage early in their careers, boxer Gene Tunney, who worked out in the gym, and former New York City mayor Ed Koch, who studied at the Music School (whose faculty included, over the years, such distinguished artists as Edgar Varese and John Cage.) In addition, Eleanor Roosevelt, Amelia Earhart and John Dewey, who served as head of the Greenwich House Education Committee, were frequent visitors in the Settlement's early years.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Greenwich House Records (Tamiment #139).
Helen Murphy Greenwich House Children's Theatre Papers (Tamiment #139.1).
Greenwich House Annual Reports, 1902-1960, were microfilmed and are available on two reels (Tamiment R 7089/1-2).
General Photographs Collection – Greenwich House (Photographs #1 – Folder #172).
Scope and Content Note
The Greenwich House Photographs Collection consists of ca. 4,750 black and white photographs; ca. 1,950 black and white negatives and 119 slides. It contains a unique group of images pertaining to social welfare and the settlement movement over a period of more than seventy years. The dates covered are 1902 - 1986; the bulk of the photographs were taken prior to 1970. They are strongest in documenting the programs of Greenwich House (particularly those involving children and fine and applied arts instruction, such as its Pottery School, and its Music School, and its summer camps, Camps Herbert Parsons and Wanamaker), as well as its administrative and institutional activities. They are also valuable in documenting many aspects of the lives of immigrants and working people in New York City: Greenwich House social events, for example, detail the complex interactions between different ethnic groups, and images of street vistas in New York City offer information on community life in Greenwich Village. The numerous images of children also yield information on dress and demeanor of working class children in New York City through time. The Collection may also be of interest to students of the history of photography, as it contains numerous images by noted photographers Jessie Tarbox Beals and Alfred Tennyson Beals. Images of famous Greenwich House alumni and celebrity visitors to Greenwich House are scattered throughout the collection, but are concentrated in the "Events" folders, as well as in the "Simkovich" and "Portraits, A-Z" folders. Because reproduction is restricted for a small number of the images in the Collection (due to privacy or copyright concerns), researchers should who want to publish an image (or images) from the Collection should consult archives staff to determine its copyright status.
Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Nursery schools |z United States.; Social settlements -- New York (State) -- New York.; Black-and-white photographs.; Slides (photographs); Black-and-white negatives.; Camps |z United States.; Kindergarten |x Activity programs |z United States.; Torn, Rip, 1931-2019; Simkhovitch, Mary K. (Mary Kingsbury), 1867-1951; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Greenwich House (New York, N.Y.); Koch, Ed, 1924-2013; Earhart, Amelia, 1897-1937; Greenwich House (New York, N.Y.). Music School; Greenwich House (New York, N.Y.). Pottery School; Cooperative Social Settlement Society of the City of New York; Gulkin, Anita Kurman
- Series I: Photographic Prints, 1902-1991.
  - Antique Shows (42 photographs, 7 contact sheets), 1950, 1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Antique Shows-Committee, 1962, 1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Antique Shows-Antiques (51 photographs, 3 contact sheets), 1967-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arts and Crafts-Children (see also Nursery School/Child Care) (55 photographs, 2 contact sheets, 8 small contact prints), 1965-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Athletics-Awards Ceremonies (see also Staff-Portraits-Antonelli, Fred) (80 photographs), 1949-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Athletics-Baseball-Boys (3 photographs), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Athletics-Basketball-Boys (33 photographs), 1922-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Athletics-Basketball-Boys (40 photographs), 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Athletics-Basketball-Boys (14 photographs), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Athletics-Basketball-Girls (10 photographs), 1928-1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Athletics-Boxing-Boys (55 photographs), 1926-1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Athletics-Boxing-Girls (2 photographs), 1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Athletics-Gymnastics (5 photographs), 1928, [1930s] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Athletics-Miscellaneous (1 archery, 2 fencing, 1 wrestling, 1 football, 1 track) (6 photographs), [1930s-1950s] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Automobile Racetrack [relation to Greenwich House unclear] ( 3 photographs), [1950s] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Awards Ceremonies (37 photographs, 1 contact sheet), 1959 -1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Baton Class-Teens (1 photograph), [1960] (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Betsy Head Memorial Playground (2 photographs), 1916 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Board Members-Event-Rosenburg Art Gallery (8 photographs), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Board Members-Portraits (48 photographs), 1926, 1951, 1953, [1910s-1950s] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Board Members-Unidentified (42 photographs, 3 contact sheets, 4 small contact prints), [1920s-1930s, 1950s- 1960s] (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Boy Scouts (3 photographs), 1970, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brotherhood Annual Dinner/Awards (60 photographs), 1964-1974, [1960s-1970s] (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Brotherhood Rally (4 photographs), [1959] (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House (15 photographs, 1 photograph of sketches), [1910s -1920s, 1950s] (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House-Auditorium (6 photographs), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House-Bungalow-Midland Beach, Staten Island, 1927 (1 photograph) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House-Jones Street and Barrow Street (32 photographs, 1 small contact print), 1928-1982, [1910s-1980s] (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House-Original Greenwich House Building (1 photograph), [1900s] (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Camp-Departure (42 photographs), 1965, 1977, [1930s-1940s, 1970s-1980s] (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Camp-Caravan to Camp (53 photographs, 6 contact sheets), [1954, 1957, 1958] (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Camp-Camp Herbert Parsons (126 photographs), 1923 -1941, [1920s-1940s] (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Camp-Camp Herbert Parsons (168 photographs, 11 contact sheets, 7 small contact prints), [1940s-1950s] (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Camp-Camp Herbert Parsons (59 photographs), [1950s-1960s] (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Camp-Camp Herbert Parsons (168 photographs, 11 contact sheets, 134 photographs), 1950 -1991, [1950s-1980s] (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Camp-Camp Staff-Portraits (see also Staff-Portraits) (3 photos), [1910s, 1960s] (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Camp-Camp Wanamaker (59 photographs), [1900s, 1940s – 1950s] (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Camp-Camp Wanamaker (19 photographs), 1937-1945 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Camp-Camp Wanamaker (15 photographs), 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Camp-West Brighton, S.I. (see also Buildings-Greenwich House-Midland Beach Bungalow, S.I.) (4 photographs), 1929, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Ceramics-Seniors (9 photographs), undated [1960s-1980s] (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Children-Children with Animals (12 photographs), undated [1920s, 1950s] (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Children-Classroom Shots (2 photographs), undated [1950s] (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Children-Children's Plays, Pageants, Parades and Puppets (48 photographs), 1916-1935, [1910s -1930s, 1940s] (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Children-"Children of Former Residents of Greenwich House" (disassembled scrapbook) (17 photographs), 1912-1924, [1920s] (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Children-Disassembled Children's Photographic Booklet (8 photographs), 1964-1974, [1960s-1970s] (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Children-Groups (23 photographs), [1900s, 1950s] (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Children-Nutritional Support/Feeding Programs (see also Cooking Class-Adults, Children and Portraits) (53 photographs), 1920s-1950s, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Children-Outing-Bronx Park (5 photographs), 1933 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Children-Outing-Bronx Zoo (2 photographs, 5 contact sheets), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Children-Outing-Wood Craft Hike (1 photograph), 1929 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Children-Outings-Miscellaneous (30 photographs), 1928-1931, [1920s-1980s] (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Children-Outings-Bath Beach and Other Beaches (5 photographs), [1910s -1920s] (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Children-Playing (6 photographs, 2 contact sheets), [1970s-1980s] (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Children-Playing in Washington Square Park/Central Park (27 photographs), 1959, 1965, [1940s-1950s] (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Children-Rooftop Bathing/Sun Bathing (21 photographs, 1 contact sheet), [1920s-1950s] (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Children-Street Games (12 photographs), [1920s-1980s] (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Clinic-Babies and Children (9 photographs), 1928-1932, [1910s -1940s] (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Clinic-Dental (3 photographs), [1910s-1920s] (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Clinic-Posture (24 photographs), 1924, 1926, 1934, [1920s] (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Clubs and Associations-Adult (9 photographs), 1923-1949, [1920s, 1940s] (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Cooking Class-Adults, Children (4 photographs), 1902, [1920s-1940s] (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Dan Cooper Showroom (23 photographs), 1953, 1954, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Dance Class-Adults (10 photographs, 1 contact sheet), [1940s, 1960s] (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Dance Class-Children (24 photographs, 1 contact sheet), 1964, [1940s -1970s] (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Dancing-Social Occasions (11 photographs), [1950s -1960s] (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Drawing Class-Adults (3 photographs, 1 contact sheet), [1920s-1950s] (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Drawing Class-Children's (see also Children) (5 photographs), 1950, [1920s -1940s] (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - English Classes (5 photographs, 1 contact sheet), [1940s-1950s] (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Annual Performances at New York Savings Bank (34 photographs, 1 contact sheet), 1949-1956, [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Addicts Tell It Like It Is" (7 photographs), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Campaign Against Teen Drug Use at Bank of Federal Savings (8 photographs), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Christmas Parties (35 photographs, 6 contacts, 3 small contact prints), 1957, [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Christmas Sales (15 photographs), 1947, 1954, 1980, [1954, 1960s] (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Eleanor Roosevelt and Mary Simkhovitch Radio Broadcast (3 mounted photographs), [1930s] (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Eleanor Roosevelt Visits Greenwich House (5 photographs), [1930s] (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Gourmet Shows (25 photographs), 1954, 1955, [1954, 1955] (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Greenwich House Children's Art Show" (20 photographs), 1949, [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Greenwich House Parade (8 photographs), 1959, [1959] (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Halloween Party (6 photographs), [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Events-Greenwich House-JAL Seminar in Japanese Culture (33 photographs), [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Jones Street Play, 1941" (5 photographs) (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Events-Greenwich House-MacDougal Alley Open House Fund Raiser (5 photographs), 1962, [1962] (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Mirror Youth Forum (8 photographs), 1944-1951 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Miscellaneous (4 photographs, 16 small contact prints), 1959, [1950s-1960s] (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Mothers and Kids Event" (6 photographs), [1950s] (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Music Festival: May 1931" (2 photographs) (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Musical Tea from Greenwich House Music School" (1 photograph), 1927 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Open House (7 photographs), [1950s] (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Publicity for "Bazaar 1951"-pet show (2 photographs) (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Pottery-"CBS-Let's Take a Trip" (2 photographs), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Radio Broadcast (4 photographs), [1960s-1970s] (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Rooftop Plays and Parties (9 photographs), 1924, [1920s] (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Puppet Show (3 photographs), [1920s-1930s] (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Social Events-Adult (5 photographs, 1 small contact print), 1919-1922, [1922, 1950s] (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Veterans' Event (5 photographs), 1970, [1970s] (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Westside Savings Bank (2 photographs), [1950s] (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Financial Contributors and Sponsors (7 photographs), 1940s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Financial Sponsors with Children (59 photographs), 1965, 1966, [1950s-1960s] (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Former Greenwich House Associates (25 photographs), 1919-1942, [1920s-1940s] (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Glee Club (1 photograph), [1930s] (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Greater NY Fund Visiting Group in Child Care Center and Pottery (25 prints), [1960s] (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Greenwich House Brochure (16 photographs), 1964, 1967, [1960s] (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Greenwich House-60th Year of Service 1962-disassembled scrapbook (7 small contact prints) (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Greenwich House postcard, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 039)
  - Greenwich Village Parade (FOLDER MISSING), undated (Box not specified, Folder 105)
  - Group Work-Children and Adult (17 photographs), [1930s-1950s] (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Instruction and Supervision (11 photographs), 1940, 1941, undated [1920s-1940s] (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Kindergarten (14 photographs, 1 small contact print), 1926, 1931, undated [1910s-1960s] (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Lace Making Class and Lace Pieces (12 photographs), [1900s] (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Miscellaneous Greenwich House-related photographs (14 photographs), 1981, [1950s -1960s] (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Miscellaneous-No apparent relationship to Greenwich House (27 photographs, 10 contact prints), 1961-1967, [1920s-1960s] (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Mothers' Club (1 photograph), [1920] (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Music School Building (see also Buildings-Greenwich House) (8 photographs), 1948 (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Music School Classes-Children (48 photographs, 2 contact sheets, 9 contact prints), [1920s-1960s] (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Music School-Concerts (27 photographs), 1928, 1934, 1951, [1920s -1950s] (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Music School-Miscellaneous (4 photographs), undated, 1920s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Music School-Portraits (17 photographs, 4 contact sheets), 1925, 1928, 1963, [1930s -1960s] (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Music School-Rehearsals (21 photographs, 15 contact sheets), 1942, [1930s-1970s] (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - New York City-Streetscapes and Vistas (15 photographs), 1927, [1920s -1930s] (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - New York City-Streetscapes and Vistas-MacDougal Alley (publicity photos for MacDougal Alley Open House Fund Raiser) (8 photographs), [1900, 1960s] (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - New York City-Streetscapes and Vistas-Brooklyn Bridge-East River Views (2 photographs), [1920s] (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - Nursery School/Child Care (see also Arts and Crafts-Children) (9 photographs), [1950s] (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - Nursery School/Child Care (see also Arts and Crafts-Children) (7 photographs), [1950s] (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - Portraits-A to Z (alphabetical list follows) (24 photographs), [1920s -1960s] (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - Nursery School/Child Care (see also Arts and Crafts-Children) (83 photographs, 4 contacts, 24 contact prints), 1965, [1920s -1960s] (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Photographs Formerly Attached to Correspondence (14 photographs), 1934-1976, [1910s-1970s] (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Photography Class-Children (6 photographs, 6 contact sheets), [1950s] (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Photographs by Alfred Tennyson Beals and Jessie Tarbox Beals (additional photographs shot by them are located through the collection) (28 photographs), 1921 -1926, [1910s -1920s] (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Photographs by Alfred Tennyson Beals and Jessie Tarbox Beals (additional photographs shot by them are located through the collection) (10 photographs), [1900s] (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Portraits-Children (see also Children-Nutritional Support and Feeding Programs) (112 photographs), 1928 -1951, [1910s-1960s] (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Portraits-Children (see also Children-Nutritional Support and Feeding Programs) (4 mounted photographs), [1920s, 1950s -1960s] (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Portraits-Incorporators of Greenwich House (4 photographs), 1904, 1926, [1903-1920] (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Adults-Individuals/Class Members (80 photographs), 1953-1982, [1910s -1980s] (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Art Photos by Ira Wright Martin (5 mounted photographs), 1926 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Children-Individuals/Class Members (15 photographs), 1915, 1917, [1910s, 1960s] (Box 8, Folder 135)